AD.MC.012
AbuDhabi
- President Mustafa Kemal Ataturk (1881-1938) and, on the right, Prime Minister Ismet Pasha (1884-1973) introducing the new turkish alphabet in Kayseri, Anatolia, Turkey. 9.1 x 14 cm, 20 September 1928; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Anatolia, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Kayseri,Turkey; Men; Mustafa Kemal Ataturk, 1881-1938; Pasha, Ismet; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Turkish Alphabet; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- Turkish Prime Minister Ismet Pasha giving a speech at a ceremony for the opening of rail service to Kayseri, Turkey. Turkish writing front and back. 11.4 x 17.1 cm, 29 May 1927; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Ceremonies; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Kayseri,Turkey; Men; Pasha, Ismet; Photographic Prints; Speech; Trains; Transportation; Turkish Writing
- Panorama of Kayseri. The clock tower, grand Bazaar and Kayseri Castle. 9.9 x 17 cm, 1927; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Architecture; Buildings; Castles; Clocks & Watches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grand Bazaar; Kayseri Clock Tower; Kayseri Grand Mosque; Kayseri,Turkey; Landscapes; Mosques; Photographic Prints
- President Mustafa Kemal Ataturk (1881-1938) and, on the right, Prime Minister Ismet Pasha (1884-1973) introducing the new turkish alphabet in Kayseri, Anatolia, Turkey. Turkish writing on the front. 17 x 12.3 cm, 20 September 1928; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Anatolia, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Kayseri,Turkey; Men; Mustafa Kemal Ataturk, 1881-1938; Pasha, Ismet; Smoking; Turkish Alphabet; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- Children at Haci Mansur Primary School in Kayseri, Turkey celebrating Republic Day with banners and traditional Turkish dress. 11.9 x 17.1 cm, 29 October 1932; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Boys; Buildings; Ceremonies; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Hats; Kayseri,Turkey; Parades; Schools / Education; Traditional Dress; Uniforms
- Self-portrait of photographer Hayri T. Tolgay. 18 x 12.9 cm, Circa 1950; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Street vendors from Port Said, Egypt. Two boys sitting and one girl standing, the girl carrying produce on her head and the boys with vegetables in a basket in front of them. On reverse side of ref159. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Studio D.H. Arnoux (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Albumen Prints; Boys; Children; Fezes / Tarbouches; Fruits & Vegetables; Girls; Hats; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Scales; Street Vendors; Studio Photography
- Woman sitting on a studio boulder fixture, holding a piece of pottery, leaning on a wide-bottomed amphora. On reverse side of ref158. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Studio D.H. Arnoux (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Albumen Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Pottery; Studio Photography; Women
- Woman reclined on a pillow, holding a hand fan with a tall pipe at her feet. French writing at the bottom: "Arab woman having her siesta in a villa near the Pyramides." 19.9 x 26.8 cm, Undated; Studio D.H. Arnoux (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Albumen Prints; Egypt; French Writing; Hand Fans; Hats; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Shoes; Smoking; Studio Photography; Women
- Hand-colored photograph of a man in a suit standing on the bank of a creek in the woods. 16.6 x 12.5 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs / Hand-tinting; Painting; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Trees; Turkey; Water
- Tomb with intricately carved wood panels. 23.6 x 31 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Arabic Calligraphy; Arabic Writing; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Windows; Wood Carvings
- Three women and a young boy standing under a tree on the banks of the Nilufer River, Gecit Korusu, Bursa, Turkey. Turkish writing on label. 30 x 25 cm, 1929; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Boys; Bursa, Turkey; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Nilufer River; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Trees; Turkish Writing; Water; Women
- A man and woman standing under a tree on the Nilufer River with a stone bridge in the background, Gecit Korusu, Bursa, Turkey. Turkish writing on label. 30 x 24.9 cm, 1908; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Bridges; Bursa, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Nilufer River; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Trees; Turkish Writing; Water; Women
- Three women, a man and a boy standing under the Nilufer Bridge, spanning the Nilufer River in Bursa, Turkey. Identified on the label as one of the first Turkish architectural monuments in Bursa. 23.4 x 29.8 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Hilal, Bakirkoy, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Boys; Bridges; Bursa, Turkey; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Nilufer River; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Trees; Turkish Writing; Water; Women
- Self-portrait of Arif Hikmet Koyunoglu standing in front of the State Art and Sculpture Museum in Ankara, Turkey. 31 x 22.8 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Ankara, Turkey; Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey; Windows
- Green Mosque in Bursa, Turkey, in the snow. 23 x 17 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3)
  Buildings; Bursa, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Green Mosque, Bursa, Turkey; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Snow; Streets
- Street cobbler in Eyup. 17.9 x 22.7 cm, 1905; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3)
  Beards; Doors; Hand Tools; Hats; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Shoes
- A Street in Bursa. 23.8 x 18.2 cm, 1908; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3)
  Architecture; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey; Doors; Houses; Jetties; Streets; Windows
- Eight soldiers of the Ottoman army ski association on the Caucasian front. 17.8 x 24 cm, 1913; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3)
  Caucasus; Dogs; Erzurum, Turkey; Group Portraits; Hats; Men; Ottoman; Snow; Snow Skis; Uniforms; Wars; World War I
- Carved wood minbar from a Turkish mosque. 31 x 23.3 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Minbars; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Turkey; Wood Carvings
- Man standing with large decorated tile. 30 x 23.2 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- Arabic script carved into decorative wood panels on a large cabinet. 30 x 23.2 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Arabic Calligraphy; Arabic Writing; Art; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Wood Carvings
- State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey, under construction. 22.8 x 31 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Ankara, Turkey; Architecture; Buildings; Construction; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey; Windows
- Hand-colored photograph of Yeni Kaplica ("new spa") thermal bath, Bursa, Turkey. 23 x 31 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Architecture; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs / Hand-tinting; Photographic Prints; Yeni Kaplica, Bursa, Turkey
- Theater hall inside the State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey. 23 x 31 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Ankara, Turkey; Architecture; Doors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey; Theater
- Selimiye Mosque, in Edirne, Turkey. View from across the nearby Tundza (Tunca) River. 23.3 x 31 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Architecture; Buildings; Edirne, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Selimiye Mosque; Trees; Tundzha River
- Self-portraits of Arif Hikmet Koyunoglu, the center portrait is from his underground studio. Turkish writing in the label on the front. 20.9 x 27.4 cm, 1915; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3)
  Fur Garments; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Shoes; Studio Photography
- Woman in a dark dress and eyeglasses, emerging through a divide in a curtain. Turkish writing on front: "Underground Photography Studio." 17.6 x 12.3 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Carpets; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- Woman in a black headscarf, sitting on a chair. Turkish writing on the front: "Underground Photography Studio." 17.8 x 12.3 cm, Undated; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- Five soldiers of the Ottoman army ski association and two Berg Forer mountain dogs sitting on the side of the Ararat mountain during the Caucasian campaign in World War I. 9 x 14 cm, 1913; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Albumen Prints; Caucasus; Dogs; Erzurum, Turkey; Group Portraits; Guns; Hats; Military / Soldiers; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Snow; Snow Skis; Turkish Writing; Uniforms; Wars; World War I
- View of Nusretli, Yozgat. Berggren. 31.6 x 36.5 cm., Undated; Berggren, Guillaume (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Albumen Prints; Countryside / Rural; Landscapes; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Zonguldak, Turkey
- View over the Grand Bazaar. Prince Islands and Sea of Marmara. 29.8 x 37.9 cm., Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Blue Mosque, Istanbul, Turkey; Bosphorous, Istanbul, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grand Bazaar; Istanbul, Turkey; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Prince Islands, Istanbul, Turkey; Sea of Marmara
- Religious procession in an Ottoman village. 19.9 x 25.6 cm., Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Gatherings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Ottoman; Photographic Prints; Religious Ceremony; Turkey
- Group photo of fifteen Ottoman military men in front of a fence. Man seated in the center wearing binoculars. Man seated at the far left wearing a riding crop. 29.6 x 35.5 cm., Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Military / Soldiers; Ottoman; Ottoman Clothing; Photographic Prints
- Rifat in Samsun. "To my dear uncle Ziya Bey". 29.6 x 35.7 cm., 28 June 33 (1917); Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Maps; Ottoman; Ottoman Clothing; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Samsun, Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Group portrait of three women and two men. Woman in the center holding a Turkish oud and man in the bottom right holding a shisha (hookah) pipe. Photo ripped diagonally on the bottom left. 29 x 39.3 cm, Undated; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Musical Instruments; Nargiles; Ottoman Clothing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Port Said, Egypt. 27.9 x 35.1 cm., Undated; Studio D.H. Arnoux (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Boats; Docks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- Family portrait with man seated with female child on his right lap, male child standing to his left, and printed nature backdrop. 31.4 x 25.8 cm., Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Boys; Children; Family Portraits; Fezes / Tarbouches; Girls; Hand-colored Photographs / Hand-tinting; Men; Military / Soldiers; Painted Backdrops; Swords & Knives; Toys; Turkey; Uniforms
- Procession of men, horses, and carriages facing to the right with men on the right-hand side facing the center. 29.9 x 36.2 cm., Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Albumen Prints; Carriages & Coaches; Horses; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- Group photo of Ottoman military officials and two young boys standing underneath an archway with the Ottoman flag hanging inside the entrance to the left. Arabic writing stamp on back. 30 x 35.5 cm, Undated; Nalbandian, Y. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Albumen Prints; Arabic Writing; Boys; Fezes / Tarbouches; Group Portraits; Men; Military / Soldiers; Mustaches; Ottoman; Photographic Prints; Swords & Knives; Turkey; Uniforms
- Group of men on horseback in traditional dress, a group of men and women in traditional dress standing and sitting on an embankment in the background, and an Ottoman soldier in uniform standing with a sword in the center foreground. 25 x 30 cm, Undated; Nalbandian, Y. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Horses; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Swords & Knives; Traditional Dress; Turkey; Uniforms; Women
- Group of soldiers and govenrment officials praying, standing at the top and base of the exterior staircase leading to the second floor terrace of a brick building. 25 x 30 cm, Undated; Nalbandian, Y. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Baghdad, Iraq; Beards; Buildings; Fezes / Tarbouches; Flags; Men; Military / Soldiers; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Praying; Religious Ceremony; Religious Clothing; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
- Large group of men standing to the sides of a path entering a building with striped guard towers on either side of the doorway. The men are praying, led by a religious figure in the center and a band with a drum and brass intruments stand to the right. Arabic writing stamp on the back. 30 x 35.1 cm, Undated; Nalbandian, Y. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Men; Military / Soldiers; Music |x Performance; Musical Instruments; Photographic Prints; Praying; Religion; Religious Ceremony; Swords & Knives; Turkey; Uniforms
- A group of soldiers pray in front of their barracks, led by an imam in light colored religious dress standing on a platform. A group of men, including German military leaders, are gathered on the right in front of a small mosque. 29.5 x 35 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Germans; Military / Soldiers; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Praying; Religious Ceremony; Turkey; Uniforms
- A line of soldiers are reviewed by visiting military leaders. 29.5 x 35 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Canes & Walking Sticks; Germans; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Praying; Religious Ceremony; Religious Clothing; Traditional Dress; Turkey; Umbrellas; Uniforms
- Cavalry class at the Ottoman Military College. Turkish writing on back reads: "Pangalti Mekteb-i Harbiye (Ottoman Military College) 1918." 29.5 x 30 cm, 5 June 1918; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Boots; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Hats; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Military / Soldiers; Mustaches; Officers; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Uniforms
- Dr. William Goodell (1792–1867), a Christian missionary. 28.5 x 25.8 cm, 1860; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Beards; Bow Ties; Men; Photographic Prints; Religion; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Dirt road bending to the right in the distance. The road is on the side of a hill with trees on both sides. 23.7 x 27.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Landscapes; Nature; Photographic Prints; Roads; Trees; Turkey
- Portrait of a man in a wool collared shirt with dark hair parted on his right, looking off to the left. 28 x 21.7 cm, 7 May 1918; Bahaeddin, Rahmizade; Studio Photo Resna, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 4)
  Constantinople; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- Mosque portal from the Nuruosmaniye Mosque with muqarnas and plaque with Arabic writing. 26.9 x 20.9, 1900; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Arabic Calligraphy; Architecture; Doors; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mosques; Nuruosmaniye Mosque, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
- Studio portrait of Fazil and Fazilet. 28 x 18.9, 27 September 1928; Studio Photo Yeni Dunya (Box 4)
  Books; Boys; Children; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- Man with a mustache, wearing a fez and a high-collared shirt with a dark tie, looking off to the left. 24.9 x 16.6 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Resna, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 4)
  Constantinople; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Group photo with numerous men in light-colored military uniforms, some standing and some sitting in the yard of a building among some foliage. 18.4 x 25.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Canes & Walking Sticks; Flags; Group Portraits; Hand Fans; Hats; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Swords & Knives; Turkey; Uniforms; Women
- Man with beard holding a long-handled whip, wearing high leather boots with spurs, a brimmed hat and a wide printed cummerbund around his waist. His right foot is set on a pedestal and his right hand on a tilted column. 22.6 x 21.6 cm, Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Beards; Boots; Constantinople; Hats; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- Tree of the Janissaries in the courtyard of the Topkapi Palace. 25.6 x 20.5 cm, Circa 1894; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Animals; Buildings; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Topkapi Palace; Trees
- Toddler girl in a light-colored lace-trimmed dress, sitting on an upholstered curule seat. Turkish writing on back: "Gift from the Armenian Patriarchate of Istanbul." 27.5 x 17.3 cm, Undated; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Children; Constantinople; Furnishings; Girls; Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- Ottoman Pasha and the head guard of Wilhelm II in Baalbek. 23.6 x 30.2 cm, Undated; Akozer, Ali Sami (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites; Baalbek, Lebanon; Fezes / Tarbouches; Hats; Military / Soldiers; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
- Panoramic view of Istanbul overlooking the Golden Horn. 20.5 x 26.1 cm, 1894; Sebah, Pascal (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Boats; Bosphorous, Istanbul, Turkey; Bridges; Galata Bridge; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Steamboats; The Golden Horn
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress with four men standing in front with a boy seated on the bridge. 19.9 x 25.1 cm., 1860; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Boys; Eating; Food; Istanbul, Turkey; Landscapes; Men; Photographic Prints; Street Vendors; Turkey; Yedikule Fortress, Istanbul, Turkey
- Tomb of Sultan Selim II with man seated on left hand side of the door and tiled art on either side. 21 x 26.9 cm., 1895; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Arabic Calligraphy; Hagia Sophia; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Tombs
- Nuruosmaniye Mosque Gate with street vendors. 20.9 x 26.7 cm., Circa 1890; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Arabic Calligraphy; Architecture; Doors; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mosques; Nuruosmaniye Mosque, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Shoes; Street Vendors
- Interior of Bayezid I Mosque (Yildirim Sultan Bayazid) with four men kneeling and chandaliers hanging low. 26.6 x 20.7 cm., 1894; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Bursa, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Religious Ceremony
- The tree of the Janissaries with 3 men to the left, one man hidden in the hollow, and one man to the right of the tree. 21.8 x 26.8 cm., 1889; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Nature; Photographic Prints; Topkapi Palace; Trees
- Bayezid II Mosque exterior with pigeons in the courtyard. 21.2 x 26.8 cm., 1890; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Birds; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Street Vendors; Trees
- Ablution fountain outside the Bayezid II Mosque. 21.6 x 26.6 cm., 1894; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Bayezid II Mosque; Birds; Fountains; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mosques; Photographic Prints
- Suleymaniye Mosque exterior. 20.8 x 26.9 cm., 1900; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Suleymaniye Mosque; Trees
- Sideview of Cifte Minareli Medrese with four people standing by the gate and one man standing to the left and a person carrying stacks of cloth across the street. 23.9 x 17.5 cm., Undated; Unknown (Box 4)
  Archaeological Sites; Erzurum, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Turkish Writing
- Train and bridge on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 19 x 25.5 cm., Undated; Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Bridges; Men; Photographic Prints; Railways; Trains; Turkey
- Military Academy cadets standing before a bridge on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 25.8 x 19 cm., 1891; Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Bridges; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Railways; Swords & Knives; Trains; Turkey; Uniforms
- Ottoman military academy students and rail workers standing in front of a train tunnel on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 19 x 25.4 cm., Undated; Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Railways; Trains; Turkey; Uniforms
- Ottoman military academy students and railway workers standing in front of a tunnel on the Istanbul - Ankara Railway. Turkish writing on attached paper. 14.3 x 14 cm, 1891; Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin (Box 4)
  Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Railways; Trains; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- Major General Giritli Ismail of the Ottoman cavalry. 16.8 x 23 cm, Circa 1890; Akozer, Ali Sami (Box 4)
  Albumen Prints; Fezes / Tarbouches; Horses; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Uniforms
- Kaiser Wilhelm II during his visit to Umayyad Mosque in Damascus. 23.5 x 32.5 cm, 1898; Akozer, Ali Sami (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Damascus, Syria; Flags; Hats; Men; Military / Soldiers; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- Actors on a stage performing a production based on the battle of Sakarya. Turkish writing on the back. 11.5 x 17.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Arabic Writing; Costumes; Ottoman Writing; Performance Plays; Photographic Prints; Theater; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Wars
- The interior courtyard of the Manisa Sultan Mosque. 17 x 12.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Manisa Sultan Mosque; Manisa, Turkey; Men; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Turkish Writing
- Two three-masted ships in a body of water with mountains in the background. 11.9 x 16.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Clouds; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains; Photographic Prints; Seas; Ships; Turkey
- Groups of men in bowler and cylander hats and men in traditional dress standing among a group of sitting haltered and saddled camels. 11.4 x 15.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Beards; Camels; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Turkey
- Group of seven men standing and sitting in front of the Porch of the Caryatids at the Erechtheion Temple on the north side of the Acropolis in Athens, Greece. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Acropolis of Athens; Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites; Athens, Greece; Erechtheion Temple; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; The Porch of the Caryatids